Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts collection
1701-2007
1701-1987
MS 1258
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
44.77
(83 boxes)
An artificial collection of correspondence, writings, diaries, and memorabilia relating to Yale University, its officials and employees, faculty, students, and related topics.
Existence and Location of Copies
Yale Miscellaneous Manuscript No. 77, Warner Thornton McGuinn scrapbook relating to politics and civil rights in Baltimore, Maryland, 1901-1918 is available on microfilm (157 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM198.
Nathaniel W. Taylor's journal of a voyage to Hurd's Island, 1857-1859, in Series I, is available on microfilm (66 frames on 1 reel, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM268.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Alphabetical (by author). II. Numerical (by order of acquisition).
Scope and Contents
Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts is a collection of material which pertains primarily to Yale and its graduates, and includes such items as correspondence, diaries, writings, and memorabilia. The collection spans the entire history of Yale; a significant portion of the holdings dates from the eighteenth century.
The collection consists of two series. Series I is arranged alphabetically by author. Series II is arranged numerically in order of acquisition.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
College students -- Biography; New Haven (Conn.); Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Adams, Daniel, 1773-1864; Adams, John, 1750?-1814; Alexander, Caleb, 1755-1828; Andrews, Charles McLean, 1863-1943; Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1869-1956; Bacon, Epaphroditus Champion; Bacon, Francis, 1820-1849; Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1881; Baldwin, Roger Sherman, 1826-1856; Beard, Augustus Field, 1833-1934; Beers, Henry A. (Henry Augustin), 1847-1926; Berdan, John Milton; Bigelow, Poultney, 1855-1954; Bingham, Harold C. (Harold Clyde), 1888-1964; Blumer, George, 1872-1962; Brewster, Chauncey B. (Chauncey Bunce), 1848-1941; Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893; Browning, Philip Embury, 1866-; Bumstead, Horace, 1841-1919; Castle, Benjamin; Catlin, George, 1796-1872; Childs, Daniel Brewer; Dahl, Lewis Curtis; Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1849-1935; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895; Dana, James, 1735-1812; Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867; DeForest, Othniel; Dudley, Samuel William, 1879-1963; Edwards, Benjamin; Edwards, Franklin; Edwards, Jonathan, 1703-1758; Eliot, Gustavus, 1857-1932; Elkin, William Lewis, 1855-1933; Evarts, John Jay; Farrand, Beatrix, 1872-1959; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Foch, M. Ferdinand; Gibbs, Josiah W. (Josiah Willard), 1790-1861; Goodrich, Chauncey A. (Chauncey Allen), 1790-1860; Goodrich, Chauncey Shafter; Goodrich, Elizur, 1734-1797; Grant, John Mason, 1817-1878; Griswold, Alfred Whitney, 1906-1963; Hale, Enoch, 1753-1837; Hale, Nathan, 1755-1776; Halsted, William, 1852-1922; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961; Hess, George; Ives, Charles, 1874-1954; Ives, Eli, 1779-1861; Ives, Robert S.; Jennings, William Jesup; Johnston, Henry Phelps, 1842-1923; Kellogg, Stephen W. (Stephen Wright), 1822-1904; Ladd, George Trumbull, 1842-1921; LaFarge, Louis Bancel, 1900-; Lee, William H.; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822; Minnigerode, Meade, 1887-1967; Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1822-1908; Munson, Stephen; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964; Norton, Edward, 1969-; Peck, Tracy, 1838-1921; Radtke, Leonard B.; Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945; Seymour, Origen Storrs, 1872-1940; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Stagg, Amos Alonzo, 1862-1965; Stimson, Henry A. (Henry Albert), 1842-1936; Taft, Horace Dutton, 1861-1943; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Trumbull, John, 1750-1831; Tully, William, 1785-1859; Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1894-1972; Connecticut. General Assembly; Mory's Association; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Description and travel; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale University -- Students; Dwight Hall (Yale University)
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Abbe, Elizabeth F.: notes and lists on Latin and Greek readings, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acacia Club: petition for a charter, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Dean: TLS to Frederick Exton and George Parmly Day, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Daniel: 14 ALS to his son, Daniel Lucius Adams: Transferred to Misc MSS A, 1833-1835 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adorns, John: ALS to James Kingsley or tutors of Yale College, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adams, John C.: ALS from Augustine Birrell, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Joseph: photostat of letter to his father, Abraham Adams, 1738 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adams, Norman I.: ALS from James Dwight Dana and John Pardee, 1884-1885 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adee, George A.: sketch by David B. Delevan, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alden, Carroll S.: letter fragment to "Phelps" Transferred to William L. Phelps Papers Mss 578, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alden, Cyrus: photostat of letter to Kilborn Whitman, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alexander, Arthur C.: ALS to cousin "Erdy" and uncle, David D. Baldwin, 1885-1886, 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alexander, Caleb: transcripts of sermons, Circa 1780 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alexander, Walter S.: ALS to Henry White, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Allis, Henry W.: valentine from Ella: transferred to Allis Family Papers Mss 1368, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Altschul, Frank: transferred to Frank Altschul Papers, Mss 909 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alvord, Samuel: ALS to unnamed correspondent, 1797 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anderson, Frederick: TLS to Elizabeth Mitchell, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Anderson, William G.: TM about his involvement with the Chautauqua Institute. Transferred to Yale Misc Mss 155, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Andrews, Charles M.: ALS to George Parmly Day Transferred to George Parmly Day Papers Mss 174, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Andrews, Ethan A.: transferred to the Ethan A. Andrews Papers, Mss 761 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Andrews, William: ALS to his son, William Watson Andrews, and ALS from Jeremiah Day, 1830-1831 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Anonymous: scenes from a play [performed by Yale class of 1831?] (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Anonymous: diary of a [Yale faculty member?] in German, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Arvine, Earliss P.: daily journal, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Asakawa, Kan-Ichi: transferred to the Kan-Ichi Asakawa Papers, Mss 40 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Atterbury, Grosvenor: pencil sketches of Yale University and faculty, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Atwater, Jeremiah: ALS to Dwite Foster, 1793 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Avery, Charles: ALS to Joshua Spencer, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Avery, Daniel D.: ALS to his mother, Mrs. M.A. Avery, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Avery, John: 2 ALS to his sister, Eunice Avery, 1843, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Backus, C.A.: ALS to Henry R. Bond, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Backus, Elijah: diary (Transferred to Backus Family Papers MSS 47), 1778 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Backus, Thomas: ALS to James Backus (Transferred to Backus Family Papers MS 47), 1809 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bacon, Asa: resolutions passed upon his death, 1857-1858 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bacon, Epaphroditus Champion: TS thanking Francis B. Trowbridge for a gift in memory of E.G. Bacon, clippings, 1937, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bacon, Francis: army commissions, resolution at his death signed by Ethan Allen, 1847, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Bacon, Leonard: ALS and receipt to L.M. Bates, copy of Bacon's last writing, 1872, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bagby, English: notes taken by Emerson Sewall in Bagby's class, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Baker, George P.: TLS to Prof. Jack R. Crawford Transferred to Jack R. Crawford Papers MSS. 153, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Baldwin, Elijah: diary, 1810-1815 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Baldwin, George W.: TL to "Dear Mr. Treasurer" [G.P. Ray?], TLS from A. Whitney Griswold to Mrs. Harold G. Holcombe, 1924, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Baldwin, Henry: 2 ALS from Bucklin Mathewson, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Baldwin, Roger S.: ALS to Selah B. Strong, 1828 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman: TLS to Tad Jones, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Baldwin, Simeon E.: ALS to H.R. Hinckley, resolution founding a singing society: transferred to Baldwin Family papers, Ms. Gr. No. 55, 1859, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Banbury, Richard F.
    General note
    See: Box 4, folder 141
  - Bangs, John K.: ALS from Ellsworth Ford, E.W. Levering, and J.S. Kilmer to Dean Wright, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Banner, Peter: ADS from Timothy Dwight, John Treadwell, David Ely, and James Hillhouse, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Banner Publications: emendation to constitution, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Barnard, E.H.: ALS to his father, Timothy Barnard, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Barnard, Henry: ALS to ___ Schommaker, 2 ANS from Georg Bunsen to Carl Schaarschmidt; passports, marriage certificate, other documents; ALS to Chauncey Barnard, Jr.; circular for Family School, Hartford, 1833-1897, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Barnes, C.W.: school essay, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Barnes, Harvey: ADS "Constitution for the purpose of improvement of literature" by Charles Norton, Harvey Barnes, Samuel Todd, and John Beach, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Barnes, Henry B.: ALS to his father, ALS from Alfred Barnes, financial papers and clippings, ALS from F. Schroeder, 1864-1887 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Barnett, Francis B.: thesis for Bachelor of Divinity degree, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Barnum, S.W.: ALS from William H. Gilborn, ALS from Luther Beecher, 1868, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Barnum, Thomas R.: correspondence, 1919-1930 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Barr, Lockwood: 5 Yale drawings, TS on the New Haven Clock Company, 1905, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Barrows, Elijah P.: ALS to Samuel Farrar, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bartholomew, M.: transferred with the Bartholomew Papers to the Music Library (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Bartlett, Edward G.: 2 ALS to James P. Walker, 1842-1843 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Bartlett, John: ALS to his father, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Bartlett, Shubael: ALS to his brother, John Bartlett, 1802 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Bassett, William E.: ALS to Yale College faculty, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Bates, Elijah: transferred to Bates Family Papers, Mss 65 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Bates, Henry: financial documents, 1798-1842 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Bates, Isaac C.: transferred to Bates Family Papers, Mss 65 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Bates, Joshua: ALS to unnamed correspondent, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Bates, Robert C.: ALS to Andrew Keogh: Transferred to YRG 32 - C, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope: TLS to Carl Lohmann enclosing annotated copy of Yale and New Haven, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Beall, Frank H.: ALS to Miss Buckeley, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Beard, Augustus F.: correspondence, 1920-1933 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Beebe, William: transferred to William Beebe Papers, Mss 907 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Beede, John F.: ALS to Charles Seymour, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Beers, C.: ALS to Arthur Brewer, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Beers, Henry A.: correspondence, 1866-1898, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Beers, J.P.: bill from J.P. Beers' Drug Store to George W. Mead, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Bellinger, Alfred R.: poem, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Benavente, Jacinto: autographed menu, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Berden, John M.:
    - Correspondence on the occasion of his retirement from Stephen Vincent Benet, Sinclair Lewis, Henry R. Luce, Archibald MacLeish, Cole Porter, Thorton Wilder, and others; clippings, 1941, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Grade books for his English courses, 1904-1922 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Bergen, Francis: 9 ALS and TLS to Henry Emerson Tuttle, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Berger, Augustus B.: 2 poems, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Betts, S.R.: transferred to Betts Autograph Collection, Mss 603 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Bigelow, Otis M.: ALS to his sister, Mary ("Mame") Abigail Bigelow, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Bigelow, Poultney: 2 APS to Mrs. Mary W. Pryde, 1939, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Bill, Alfred R.: ALS to Dr. Phelps, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Billings, Noyes: correspondence, 1808-1828 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Bingham, Harold C.: photostats of permit and diplomatic introductions for Yale University-Carnegie Institution African Expedition, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Bingham, Hiram: transferred to William Lyon Phelps Papers, Mss 578, and to Bingham Family Papers, Mss 81 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Binney, Horace: letters from Mary (Binney) Cadwalader, 1824-1828 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Bishop, Abraham: presidential proclamation appointing him collector for New Haven, 1803 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Bishop, William Henry: sheet music and other documents relating to the song "Khaki and the Blue" Transferred to Wm. Henry Bishop Papers MSS 83 3/9/83, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Bissell, Samuel: ALS to his sister, 1820 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Black, John W.: correspondence with his family and others, 1832-1838 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Blair, W. Lawrence: obituary notice, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Blake, Edward Foster: ALS to H. R. Hinckley with handwritten transcript: Transferred TO H.B. Hinckley Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 1230, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Blake, Henry T.: transferred to Blake Family Papers, Mss 85 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Blount, Edith: correspondence and other documents re: portrait of Archibald Blount, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Blumer, George: correspondence and limericks, 1882-1896, 1947-1954 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Boies, W.E.: ALS to Yale Alumni Weekly, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Borup, George: correspondence re the Perry Expedition to the North Pole, 1908-1911 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Bostwick, Arthur E.: issue of the South Middle Salmugundi, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Bostwick, Henry P.: ALS to the Yale College faculty from Eben E. Beardsley, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Bouchet, Edward A.: ALS to George L. Fox Transferred to George L. Fox Papers Mss 975 11/82NR, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Bousman, H. Hugh: correspondence and other documents concerning the missionary work of Hugh and Nora Bousman, 1924-1942 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Bouton, Eugene: 2 ALS to Yale Dean of the Academic Department, and Hollon Farr, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Bouton, Nathaniel: ALS to Frank M. Etting, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Bradley, Frederick T.: notes on Naphtali Daggett, undated (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Brainard, Dyer T.: correspondence, 1703-1854 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Brainard, Wynard: letter, clipping about Archduke hoax, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Brainerd, Israel: ALS to his father, Ezra Brainerd, and typescript of a letter about his 50th Class Reunion, 1793, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Branol, Alois: ALS to unnamed correspondent, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Brewster, Chauncey B.: reminiscences, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Brinton, Howard F.: ANS from John Mills Gilbert, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Brockesby, John: ALS to Thacher, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Brooke, Frederick H.: TLS to Fleming Newbold, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Brooks, Philips: letters from various correspondents, among them Noah Porter, 1877-1888 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Brown, Ernest W.: correspondence, 1894-1925 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Brown, Francis G.: letter from various correspondents concerning Yale football, TLS from Theodore Roosevelt, 1899-1901 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Brown, Mason: ALS to Ezeckle Farnum, 1833 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Brown, Richard B.: prize problems, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Brown, William T.: commission as a corporal, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Browne, George M.: correspondence and his father's bond for Browne's Yale tuition, 1836-1865 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Browning, Philip E.: TMS of the song "Lux et Veritas", Navy Dept. citation signed by Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1924, undated (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Brubacher, John S.: accounts while at Yale, 1916-1920 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Brush, Graham: ALS to "Mr. Greene", 1901 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Buck, Sir Peter Henry: 2 ALS to "Mary", clipping, 1946, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Budington, William Ives: ALS to Rev. A.F. Beard, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Buildings, Yale: drawing of Yale College, [ca. 1797-1803?] (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Bull, Edward: 2 ALS from E.S. Lane, record of marriage, sermon notes, 1862-1868 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Bumstead, Horace: typescript of autobiographical sketch (photostat), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Bunnell, Frank Scott: transferred to Frank Scott Bunnell Papers, Mss 1149 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Burnam, John Miller: 2 pages of manuscript draft, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Burrell, Edward Jonathan: 2 ALS to Harry Burrell, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Butler, Thomas B.: ALS to President James Buchanan, 1860 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell: ALS to J.K. Tefft, 1844 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Calhoun, Nevell M.: ALS to Allan B. Lincoln, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Calhoun, William B.: transferred to William B. Calhoun Papers, Mss 880 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Camp, Joseph: logic notebook, 1764-1766 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Campana, Joseph and Richard F. Banbury: typescript of "Yale Riots", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Caner. A.: annotated almanack, 1760 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Capron, Samuel M.: ALS to William A. Mowry, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Carpenter, F.B.: 2 receipts, 1856-1857 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Carpenter, Zachary Taylor: manuscript of a charade, [ca. 1869-1870?] (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Carrington, Henry B.: ALS to unidentified correspondent: transferred to Carrington Family Papers N. 130, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Carter, Franklin A.: ALS from William Preston Johnston, ALS from R. D. Hubbard, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Case, Leonard: correspondence and biographical sketch, 1870-1876, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Castle, Benjamin: 3 ALS from Abbie P. Ferguson, 1874-1875 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Catlin, Charles T.: correspondence, drawing, manuscript, 1901-1903, undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Catlin, George: 2 ALS from Thomas R. Lounsbury to George St. John Sheffield, ALS from George St. John Sheffield to Andrew Keogh, 1913, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Chamberlain, Theopholis: biographical note, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Chapin, David: ALS to Lewis Chapin, 1797 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Chaplin, Calvin: ALS to Henry Davis, 1801 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Chapman, E.W.: typescript of play, undated (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Chappell, Frank Valentine: ALS to his father, undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Chase, Daniel K.: ANS to "Yale College" on a printed letter, 1869 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Chauncey, Charles: ALS to Samuel W. Dana, ALS to Edmund Olmstead, 1808, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Cheney, Ward: ALS to Hollon Farr, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Childs, Daniel Brewer: correspondence, 1873-1925 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Childs, Daniel Brewer: printed matter concerning the University of Albany Law School and Yale, 1862-1906 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Chubb, Thomas C.: manuscript of a poem, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Clapp, A. Huntington: "Second Quarterly Report of Club at Mrs. Kent's", 1839 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Clapp, J.M.: manuscript of play, undated (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Clark, Charles Hopkins: biographical sketch by Howard Mansfield, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Clark, Charles Upson: typescript extracts from his diary: transferred to Charles Upson Clark Papers Mss Group # 1294 8/82, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Clark, Charles Washburn: ALS to "My dear Professor", 1898 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Clark, William Bardwell: diary, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Clarke, Frederick William: ANS from Moses Ballou to unidentified correspondent, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Close, Odle: ANS to Edward Wright, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Colby, James Fairbanks: correspondence, printed matter concerning Colby Club, 1877-1939, undated (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Coles, Nathaniel: ALS to Phoebe Coles, 1810 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Collins, William A.: ALS to Dr. T. Romeyn Beck, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Colton, Erastus: ALS to Admiral Foote, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Colton, Wendell P.: letters of condolences to Mrs. Colton, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Coney, George E.: ALS to Arthur Twining Hadley, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Conkling, Alfred R.: ALS from Professor Brush's students, undated (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Connecticut (Colony): photostats about the founding of Yale College, 1701 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Connecticut General Assembly: report of the committee on college matter for Yale College, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Conrad, Barnaby: winning entry for Wright Memorial Prize, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Converse, George S.: correspondence, farewell address before the Brothers in Unity, 1850-1851 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Cook, Sidney A.: ALS to "Mrs. Hopkins" with news clipping, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Cook, Increase: two certificates of copyright, 1812-1813 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Cooley, Timothy M.: oration in Hebrew delivered at commencement, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Cooper, Samuel E.: correspondence and receipts, 1861-1869 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - (Yale) Corporation: resolutions and correspondence, 1734-1835, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Cowles, Horace: letters to Cowles, 1799-1819 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Crapo, William W.: ALS to B. Perry, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Crawford, Albert B.: "Gaby Delys and Yale" (typescript), undated (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Crawford, Beale B.: agreement to pay Yale term bill, 1832 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Creevey, John K.: correspondence and Yale memorabilia, 1865-1867 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Crehore, Albert C.: typescripts re: crystalline graphite and accompanying ALS, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Cromwell, George: Yale class notes and essays, [ca. 1880-1883?] (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Crosby, Raymond M.: drawings, 1945, undated (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Cross, Wilbur L.: 4 ALS to William Young, 1 ALS to George Parmly Day, 1 ALS to Fritz Wiggin: Transferred to Wilbur Cross Papers Mss 155, 5/83, 1914-1917, 1934, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Crowell, Josiah B.: correspondence, mss, financial papers, 1841-1847, undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Cunningham, Hugh: typescript notes on pamphlet Seventh Book of Genesis (1874), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Curran, Henry H.: ALS to "Yale '98" and enclosed MS, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Curtis, Edward L.: 2 autographed manuscripts, [1870?] (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Curtis, Lewis B.: Transferred to Divinity Library (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Cushing, Charles C.S.: Transferred to Hadley Family Papers, Mss 985 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Dahl, Lewis Curtis: correspondence and Yale memorabilia, 1939-1942 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Dana, Edmund L.: sketch of Jeremiah Day, correspondence, 1837, 1876-1879 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Dana, [Edward S.?]: Yale class standing book, Class of 1878 [in hand of E.S. Dana?], 1875 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Dana, James: ALS to Prof. Hitchcock, receipt, 1804, 1835 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Dana, James Dwight: ALS to "Friends and Pupils of the Class of 1877" (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Dana, Samuel T.: See Yale Picture Collection (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Darby, Thomas P.: typescript book review, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Darrach, William B.: Transferred to Darrach Family Papers, Mss 167 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Davidson, Sidney W.: address at Alumni Luncheon, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Davies, Thomas F.: ALS to Jonathan R. Sanford, 1813 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Davis, Alexander J.: drawing, scrapbook, Circa 1840-1890 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Davis, Henry: avowal of faith, 1798 (Box 6, Folder 213)